Contact

Nawal Nagar, Circular Road, Barmasia B.Deoghar, Jharkhand, India -814112 7667488641 (Mobile) abhisheksingh007@outlook.in

www.linkedin.com/in/abhishekkumar-singh-07 (LinkedIn) coderakki.in (Personal)

Top Skills

Python

Java

Hadoop

Certifications

Basic Python

Android

Django

CutShort Certified Python - Basic C (Basic)

Abhishek Kumar Singh

System Engineer | Software Engineer | Competitive Coder | 5 * on HackerRank in Python| Al/ML Enthusiast Bengaluru

Summary

Working as System Engineer at FIME.

I started my IT career at Zensar on 10th June 2019. I worked there for approx 2 years as Software Engineer.

I have skillsets in Python, Hadoop, Asp. Net, Oracle, MSSql, and Android.

My area of interest is Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence.

I have been doing competitive coding for more than 5 years.

I have achieved 5 * in multiple languages on Hackerrank platform.

I am a highly motivated and dedicated person towards my career with command over coding and interpersonal skills.

I have solely completed many regulatory projects.

My colleague and seniors have commended me for my willingness to participate and my dedication to helping out where possible.

This is Abhishek Kumar Singh...

Experience

FIME

System Engineer May 2021 - Present (3 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Zensar Technologies

2 years

Software Engineer September 2020 - May 2021 (9 months)

Page 1 of 3

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Client: C Hoare & Co. - World's Fifth Oldest Bank and UK's Second

Product: Core Application

Domain: Banking and Finance -BFSI

Role: Developer

Frontend: VB.Net, Asp.Net Database: Oracle-PL SQL, MSSQL

Project – NON-LIBOR TRANSITION

Project Description: Removed Libor Rate from Bank and

Introduced New Rate Code.

Key activities performed:

- Development using Oracle SQL Developer and Notepad++.
- Oracle SQL Developer for query of Database Objects.
- Created Database scripts and stored procedures .
- Created packages and updated existing package body and specifications.

Technology/Skills/Tools used

- Tools: Oracle SQL Developer, Notepad++
- Technologies: Oracle SQL
- Skills: Development

Project – BANK CHARGES

Project Description: Introduction of new Bank Charges. Key Activities Performed:

- Development using Visual Studio, Oracle SQL Developer and Notepad++.
- Visual Studio for existing code changes.
- Oracle SQL Developer for query of Database Objects.

Technology/Skills/Tools used

- Tools: Oracle SQL Developer, Visual Studio, Notepad++
- Technologies: Oracle SQL
- Skills: Development

Junior Software Engineer

September 2019 - September 2020 (1 year 1 month)

Pune Area, India

Project Trainee

Pune Area, India

Education

IES s College of Technology, Kalikheda, Ratibad Main Road, Bhopal - 462044

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science · (2015 - 2019)

Subhash Public School

Higher Education, Science (2013 - 2014)

Dev Sangha National School

Matriculation, Science · (2008 - 2011)

Army Public School, Ranchi

Secondary Education, Science (2006 - 2008)

Kendriya Vidyalaya Borjhar

Secondary Education, Science (2000 - 2006)